In this video, I'm going to demonstrate
how you can use the slide master view
to make changes to one slide which will
then be applied to every subsequent slide
that you insert into the presentation.
So what I need to do is I need to navigate
up to the view tab and under view tab,
I would need to select slide master.
So I select slide master, that will
take me into slide master view.
Look, don't worry too much that
all of the information from your
original presentation isn't visible.
It is actually still there.
All this is doing is it's defining
the content, the layout, the design,
the fonts, the background images and
the theme that you may be using or
wish to use for each presentation.
So one of the things to remember is
that if you wish to make a change
that will be applied to all slides,
you need to select slide one.
Now I'm going to insert the company logo.
And so I've selected slide one.
And all I need to do then is go
to the insert tab, select picture
from this device, navigate to the
image, double click on the image
and it inserts it into the slide.
I can just move that up to the top and
then I'll resize that, make it quite small
and also change the transparency so it
isn't very clear and I'm happy with that.
Again, if I make a change to the font,
so if I changed the font there, if I
go to the home tab and it's Calibri
Light, headings 44 at the moment, if
I change that to Arial and, say, 54.
When I come out of the slide master.
So I have to click on the slide
master tab again, and close slide
master view that will automatically
change the size of the font.
And as you can also see, the image
has been placed at the top of every
slide within the presentation.
If I go to a new slide and
select a blank slide again.
And, and then add another title slide it
automatically adds that and the font is
automatically going to be Arial size 60.
So if I go back to the view and select
slide master again, go back to slide one.
I can also change the theme.
So if I decided that I wasn't
happy with the theme that I had
and I wanted to change it for all
slides in the presentation and all
subsequent slides I could select
a theme that I was happy with.
And then from there, once I've got that,
I couldn't then close the master view.
And again, that will change the theme
for every slide in the presentation.